Jiepu Jiang

Information School jiepu.jiang@wisc.edu
University of Wisconsin-Madison (812) 272-1970

Research Interests

My research helps people find, understand, and create text information. I apply a unique combination of information retrieval, data/text mining, and HCl methods to study search engines, conversational agents, writing assistants, and other text information systems.

Employment

Aug 2020-Present Assistant Professor, Information School, University of Wisconsin-Madison

Aug 2018-Aug 2020 Assistant Professor, Computer Science Department, Virginia Tech

May-Aug 2014 Research Intern, Microsoft Research Redmond

Education

2013-Present University of Massachusetts Amherst

Ph.D. candidate in Computer Science, M.S. in Computer Science (2016)

2009–2016 University of Pittsburgh

Ph.D. in Library and Information Science (2016)

2003–2009 Wuhan University

M.S. in Information Science (2009), B.S. in Computer Science (2007)

Publications

Refereed Journal Articles

[J6] Wei Lu, Heng Ding, and <u>Jiepu Jiang</u>. A document expansion framework for tag-based image

retrieval. Aslib Journal of Information Management, 2018.

[J5] Wei Jeng, Jiepu Jiang, and Daqing He. (2016). Users' perceived difficulties and corresponding

reformulation strategies in Google voice search. Journal of Library and Information Studies,

14(1), 25-39.

[J4] JASIST Wei Jeng, Daqing He, and <u>Jiepu Jiang</u>. (2015). User participation in an academic social

networking service: A survey of open group users on Mendeley. Journal of the Association for

Information Science and Technology, 66(5), 890-904.

[J3]		Zhen Yue, Shuguang Han, Daqing He, and <u>Jiepu Jiang</u> . (2014). Influences on query reformulation in collaborative web search. <i>Computer</i> , 47(3), 46–53.
[J2]	JASIST	Chaoqun Ni, Cassidy R. Sugimoto, and <u>Jiepu Jiang</u> . (2013). Venue-author-coupling: A measure for identifying disciplines through author communities. <i>Journal of the American Society for Information Science and Technology</i> , 64(2), 265–279.
[J1]	JIS	Dan Wu, Daqing He, <u>Jiepu Jiang</u> , Wuyi Dong, and Kim Thien Vo. (2012). The state of iSchools: An analysis of academic research and graduate education. <i>Journal of Information Science</i> , 38(1), 15–36.

Refereed Conference Papers		
		* students I advised or mentored
[C25]	WWW '22	Qiurong Song* and <u>Jiepu Jiang</u> . 2022. How Misinformation Density Affects Health Information Search. In <i>Proceedings of the ACM Web Conference</i> 2022 (WWW '22), April 25–29, 2022, Virtual Event, Lyon, France. ACM, New York, NY, USA, 10 pages. (to appear)
[C24]	CIKM '21	Zihan Gao* and <u>Jiepu Jiang</u> . 2021. Evaluating Human-AI Hybrid Conversational Systems with Chatbot Message Suggestions. In <i>Proceedings of the 30th ACM International Conference on Information and Knowledge Management</i> (CIKM'21), November 1–5, 2021, Virtual Event, QLD, Australia. ACM, New York, NY, USA, 11 pages.
[C23]	SIGIR '21 (short paper)	Sheikh Muhammad Sarwar, Felipe Moraes, <u>Jiepu Jiang</u> , James Allan. 2021. Utility of Missing Concepts in Query-biased Summarization. In <i>Proceedings of the 44th International ACM SIGIR Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval</i> (SIGIR '21), July 11–15, 2021, Virtual Event, Canada. ACM, New York, NY, USA, 5 pages.
[C22]	SIGIR '20 (short paper)	<u>Jiepu Jiang</u> and Naman Ahuja*. (2020). Response quality in human-chatbot collaborative systems. In <i>Proceedings of the 43rd International ACM SIGIR Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval</i> .
[C21]	SIGIR '19 (short paper)	Siyu Mi* and <u>Jiepu Jiang</u> . (2019). Understanding the interpretability of search result summaries. In <i>Proceedings of the 42nd International ACM SIGIR Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval</i> .
[C20]	CIKM'17	<u>Jiepu Jiang</u> and James Allan. (2017). Similarity-based distant supervision for definition sentence retrieval. In <i>Proceedings of the 26th ACM International on Conference on Information and Knowledge Management</i> . (Acceptance rate 21%)
[C19]	CIKM'17	<u>Jiepu Jiang</u> and James Allan. (2017). Adaptive persistence for search effectiveness measures. In <i>Proceedings of the 26th ACM International on Conference on Information and Knowledge Management</i> . (Acceptance rate 21%)
[C18]	SIGIR '17	<u>Jiepu Jiang</u> , Daqing He, and James Allan. (2017). Comparing in situ and multidimensional relevance judgments. In <i>Proceedings of the 40th International ACM SIGIR Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval</i> . (Acceptance rate 22%)
[C17]	CHIIR '17	<u>Jiepu Jiang</u> , Daqing He, Diane Kelly, and James Allan. (2017). Understanding ephemeral state of relevance. In <i>Proceedings of the Second ACM SIGIR Conference on Human Information Interaction and Retrieval</i> . (Best student paper award)

[C16]	WSDM '16	<u>Jiepu Jiang</u> and James Allan. (2016). Reducing click and skip errors in search result ranking. In <i>Proceedings of the 9th ACM International Conference on Web Search and Data Mining.</i> (Acceptance rate 18.2%)
[C15]	ECIR '16	<u>Jiepu Jiang</u> and James Allan. (2016). Adaptive effort for search evaluation metrics. In Proceedings of the 38th European Conference on Information Retrieval. (Acceptance rate 21%)
[C14]	CHIIR '16	<u>Jiepu Jiang</u> and Chaoqun Ni. (2016). What affects word changes in query reformulation during a task-based search session? In <i>Proceedings of the First ACM SIGIR Conference on Human Information Interaction and Retrieval</i> .
[C13]	CHIIR '16 (short paper)	<u>Jiepu Jiang</u> and James Allan. (2016). Correlation between system and user metrics in a session. In <i>Proceedings of the First ACM SIGIR Conference on Human Information Interaction and Retrieval</i> .
[C12]	CHIIR '16	Julia Kiseleva, Kyle Williams, <u>Jiepu Jiang</u> , Ahmed Hassan Awadallah, Aidan C. Crook, Imed Zitouni, and Tasos Anastasakos. (2016). Understanding user satisfaction with intelligent assistants. In <i>Proceedings of the First ACM SIGIR Conference on Human Information Interaction and Retrieval</i> .
[C11]	CHIIR '16	Shuguang Han, Daqing He, Zhen Yue, and <u>Jiepu Jiang</u> . (2016). Exploring the contextual support for collaborative information retrieval. In <i>Proceedings of the First ACM SIGIR Conference on Human Information Interaction and Retrieval</i> .
[C10]	WWW '15	<u>Jiepu Jiang</u> , Ahmed Hassan Awadallah, Rosie Jones, Umut Ozertem, Imed Zitouni, Ranjitha Gurunath Kulkarni, and Omar Zia Khan. (2015). Automatic online evaluation of intelligent assistants. In <i>Proceedings of the 24th International Conference on World Wide Web</i> . (Acceptance rate 14.1%)
[C9]	WSDM '15	<u>Jiepu Jiang</u> , Ahmed Hassan Awadallah, Xiaolin Shi, and Ryen W. White. (2015). Understanding and predicting graded search satisfaction. In <i>Proceedings of the Eighth ACM International Conference on Web Search and Data Mining</i> . (Acceptance rate 16.8%)
[C8]	SIGIR '14	<u>Jiepu Jiang</u> , Daqing He, and James Allan. (2014). Searching, browsing, and clicking in a search session: Changes in user behavior by task and over time. In <i>Proceedings of the 37th ACM SIGIR Conference on Research & Development in Information Retrieval</i> . (Acceptance rate 21%)
[C7]	SIGIR '14 (short paper)	<u>Jiepu Jiang</u> and James Allan. (2014). Necessary and frequent terms in queries. In <i>Proceedings of the 37th ACM SIGIR Conference on Research & Development in Information Retrieval</i> .
[C6]	CIKM'13	Shuguang Han, Daqing He, <u>Jiepu Jiang</u> , and Zhen Yue. (2013). Supporting exploratory people search: a study of factor transparency and user control. In <i>Proceedings of the 22nd ACM</i> International Conference on Information & Knowledge Management. (Acceptance rate 16.9%)
[C5]	HCIR '13 (short paper)	Wei Jeng and <u>Jiepu Jiang</u> . (2013). Users' perceived difficulties and corresponding reformulation strategies in voice search. In <i>Proceedings of the 7th Annual Symposium on Human-Computer Interaction and Information Retrieval</i> .
[C4]	SIGIR '13	<u>Jiepu Jiang</u> , Wei Jeng, and Daqing He. (2013). How do users respond to voice input errors? Lexical and phonetic query reformulation in voice search. In <i>Proceedings of the 36th ACM SIGIR Conference on Research & Development in Information Retrieval</i> . (Acceptance rate 19.9%)

[C3]	JCDL '13	<u>Jiepu Jiang</u> , Chaoqun Ni, Daqing He, and Wei Jeng. Mendeley group as a new source of
	(short paper)	interdisciplinarity study: How do disciplines interact on Mendeley? In <i>Proceedings of the 13th</i>
		ACM/IEEE-CS Joint Conference on Digital Libraries.
[C2]	ISSI 2011	Chaoqun Ni, Cassidy R. Sugimoto, and <u>Jiepu Jiang</u> . (2011). Degree, closeness, and
		betweenness: Application of group centrality measurements to explore macro-disciplinary
		$evolution\ diachronically.\ In\ \textit{Proceedings}\ of\ the\ 13th\ \textit{International}\ Conference\ of\ the\ \textit{International}$
		Society for Scientometrics & Informetrics.
[C1]	iConference '11	Dan Wu, Daqing He, <u>Jiepu Jiang</u> , Wuyi Dong, and Kim Thien Vo. (2011). Academic research in
		iSchools: State and implications. In Proceedings of the 2011 iConference.

Refereed Conference Posters

[P9]	iConference '16	Chaoqun Ni and <u>Jiepu Jiang</u> . (2016). Visualizing computer science communities using conference hashtags. In <i>Proceedings of the 2016 iConference</i> .
[P8]	ASIST '13	<u>Jiepu Jiang</u> , Daqing He, and Chaoqun Ni. (2013). The correlations between article citation and references' impact measures: What can we learn? In <i>Proceedings of the 76th American Society for Information Science and Technology Annual Meeting</i> .
[P7]	HCIR '13	Shuguang Han, Zhen Yue, <u>Jiepu Jiang</u> , and Wei Jeng. (2013). IRIS-IPS: an interactive people search system. In <i>Proceedings of the 7th Annual Symposium on Human-Computer Interaction and Information Retrieval</i> .
[P6]	CIKM'12	<u>Jiepu Jiang</u> , Daqing He, Shuguang Han, Zhen Yue, and Chaoqun Ni. (2012). Contextual evaluation of query reformulations in a search session by user simulation. In <i>Proceedings of the 21st ACM International Conference on Information and Knowledge Management</i> .
[P5]	CIKM'12	Zhen Yue, <u>Jiepu Jiang</u> , Shuguang Han, and Daqing He. (2012). Where do the query terms come from? An analysis of query reformulation in collaborative web search. In <i>Proceedings of the 21st ACM International Conference on Information and Knowledge Management</i> .
[P4]	SIGIR '12	<u>Jiepu Jiang</u> , Zhen Yue, Shuguang Han, and Daqing He. (2012). Finding readings for scientists from social websites. In <i>Proceedings of the 35th ACM SIGIR Conference on Research</i> & Development in Information Retrieval.
[P3]	ASIST '12	Wei Jeng, Daqing He, <u>Jiepu Jiang</u> , and Yang Zhang. Groups in Mendeley: Owners' descriptions and group outcomes. In <i>Proceedings of the 75th American Society for Information Science and Technology Annual Meeting</i> .
[P2]	JCDL '11	<u>Jiepu Jiang</u> , Daqing He, and Chaoqun Ni. (2011). Social reference: Aggregating online usage of scientific literature in CiteULike for clustering academic resources. In <i>Proceedings of the 11th Annual International ACM/IEEE Joint Conference on Digital Libraries</i> .
[P1]	iConference '11	Xuefeng Wu, Wei Lu, and <u>Jiepu Jiang</u> . (2011). Journal evaluation using the importance of

Refereed Workshop Papers

[W6]	SIGIR '13	<u>Jiepu Jiang</u> and Daqing He. (2013). Simulating user selections of query suggestions. In SIGIR '13
	workshop	Workshop on Modeling User Behavior for Information Retrieval Evaluation.

authors in co-authorship network. In Proceedings of the 2011 iConference.

[W5]	CIKM '13 workshop	Shuguang Han, <u>Jiepu Jiang</u> , Zhen Yue, and Daqing He. (2013). Recommending program committee candidates for academic conferences. In CIKM '13 Workshop on Computational Scientometrics: Theory & Applications.
[W4]	CIKM '12 workshop	Zhen Yue, Shuguang Han, <u>Jiepu Jiang</u> , and Daqing He. (2012). Search tactics as means of examining search processes in collaborative exploratory web search. In <i>the 5th CIKM Ph.D.</i> Workshop on Information and Knowledge.
[W3]	ASIST '12 workshop	<u>Jiepu Jiang</u> and Daqing He. (2012). Social reference and altmetrics: Merely fads? In METRICS 2012: Workshop on Informetric and Scientometric Research.
[W2]	INEX '08	<u>Jiepu Jiang</u> , Wei Lu, Xianqian Rong, and Yangye Gao. (2009). Adapting language modeling methods for expert search to rank Wikipedia entities. In the 7th International Workshop of the Initiative for the Evaluation of XML Retrieval.
[W1]	SIGIR '08 workshop	<u>Jiepu Jiang</u> , Shuguang Han, and Wei Lu. (2008). Expertise retrieval using search engine results. In SIGIR '08 workshop on Future Challenges in Expertise Retrieval.

Non-refereed Articles

[N6]	TREC 2014	<u>Jiepu Jiang</u> and James Allan. (2014). UMass at TREC 2014 session track. In <i>Proceedings of the</i> 23rd Text REtrieval Conference.
[N5]	TREC 2013	<u>Jiepu Jiang</u> and Daqing He. (2013). Different effects of click-through and past queries on whole-session search performance. In <i>Proceedings of the 22nd Text REtrieval Conference</i> .
[N4]	TREC 2012	<u>Jiepu Jiang</u> , Daqing He, and Shuguang Han. (2012). On duplicate results in a search session. In <i>Proceedings of the 21st Text REtrieval Conference</i> .
[N3]	TREC 2011	<u>Jiepu Jiang</u> , Shuguang Han, Jia Wu, and Daqing He. (2011). PITT at TREC 2011 session track. In <i>Proceedings of the 20th Text REtrieval Conference</i> .
[N2]	TREC 2008	<u>Jiepu Jiang</u> , Wei Lu, and Haozhen Zhao. (2008). CSIR at TREC 2008 expert search task: Modeling expert evidence in expertise retrieval. In <i>Proceedings of the 17th Text REtrieval Conference</i> .
[N1]	TREC 2007	<u>Jiepu Jiang</u> , Wei Lu, and Dan Liu. (2007). CSIR at TREC 2007 expert search task. In <i>Proceedings</i> of the 16th Text REtrieval Conference.

Teaching

UW-Madison

- LIS 351: Intro to Digital Information
- LIS 501: Introduction to Text Mining
- LIS 875: Tech Foundations of Information Sciences
- LIS 975: Seminar on AI Fairness and Explainability

Virginia Tech

- CS 3654: Intro to Data Analytics & Visualization
- CS 5604: Information Storage and Retrieval

Professional Services

Senior Program Committee & Meta Reviewer

- JCDL (2020–2021): ACM/IEEE Joint Conference on Digital Libraries
- WWW (2020–2022): International World Wide Web Conference (The Web Conference)

Program Committee (PC)

- AIRS (2016–2017): Asia Information Retrieval Societies Conference
- AAAI (2021–2022): AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence
- CIKM (2014–2020): ACM Conference on Information and Knowledge Management
- ECIR (2014-2022): European Conference on Information Retrieval
- IUI (2015–2021): ACM International Conference on Intelligent User Interfaces
- KDD (2022): ACM SIGKDD Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining
- SIGIR (2015–2022): ACM Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval
- WSDM (2016–2022): ACM International Conference and Web Search and Data Mining
- WWW (2015, 2018): International World Wide Web Conference (The Web Conference)
- CAIR (2017, 2018, 2020): International Workshop on Conversational Approaches to Information Retrieval
- Legal-AI (2018, 2019, 2020): Annual Workshop on Applications of Artificial Intelligence in the Legal Industry
- Learn-IR (2018): WSDM 2018 Workshop on Learning from User Interactions

Conference Reviewer

- CHI (2014, 2015, 2016, 2017, 2022): ACM CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems
- COLING (2010): International Conference on Computational Linguistics
- CSCW (2016, 2018): ACM Conference on Computer-supported Cooperative Work and Social Computing
- DIS (2016): ACM Conference on Designing Interactive Systems
- MobileHCI (2016): Conference on Human-Computer Interaction with Mobile Devices and Services

Journal Editorial Board

• Aslib Journal of Information Management (2021-Present)

Journal Reviewer

- ACM Transactions on Applied Perception (2020)
- ACM Transactions on Information Systems (2014, 2017, 2019, 2020, 2021)
- ACM Transactions on Social Computing (2019, 2020)
- Aslib Journal of Information Management (2021, 2022)
- Data and Information Management (2019)
- IEEE Computational Intelligence Magazine (2020)
- IEEE Transactions on Audio, Speech and Language Processing (2019)
- IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence (2017)
- Information Processing & Management (2017, 2021, 2022)
- Information Retrieval Journal (2016)
- Journal of Information Science (2018, 2020)
- Journal of the Association for Information Science and Technology (2009–2021)
- PLOS One (2013, 2014)
- World Wide Web Journal (2013, 2014)